toysrus.com.au 2019-07-21

# Toys"R"Us Privacy Statement

## Introduction to our Privacy Policy

The privacy of our website visitors and customers is of utmost importance to us, therefore we adhere closely to the National Privacy Principles under the Australian Privacy Act 1988 (as amended by the Privacy Amendment (Private Sector) Act 2000). This Privacy policy explains in general terms how Toys"R"US protects the privacy of your personal information under the National Privacy Principles. It will apply to any personal information you provide to us when registering with us on our web site www.toysrus.com.au.  It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

## What Information Do We Collect?

The types of personal information that we collect from you will depend on the circumstances of collection and on the type of service you request from us.  For example, when you wish to purchase a product from this website we collect details such as your name, email address, delivery address, mobile and telephone numbers and other information relevant to fulfill your purchase.

As we are required by law to obtain your consent to the collection of "sensitive information" (such as address, name and phone number), we will assume that you have given consent to the collection of all information you have provided to us for use in accordance with this Statement, unless you tell us otherwise.

When information such as your name, address and email address are provided on the checkout page or account sign-up pages, we assume you are providing consent for us to use this information to contact you or fullfil any orders that you have placed or are about to place. 

## How We Collect Information

We may collect personal information about you when you visit our website, when you deal with us over the telephone, send us correspondence (whether by letter, fax or email), or when you have contact with us in person. We will not collect any personal information without your consent.  We consider that your consent is granted when you complete the forms necessary to facilitate a transaction through this website.

## How We Use Your Personal Information

We generally collect your personal information for the following purposes:

  * To facilitate your access to our website, products and services.
  * To deliver products you have ordered from us.
  * To conduct marketing activities.
  * To provide you with information about our products and services.
  * To seek your opinion on our products, services, marketing and website.
  * To send you a newsletter if you subscribe.

Some of the personal information that we collect is essential for us to be able to accurately identify who is using the service.  Other types of personal information we collect help us to develop a profile of who is using our service and what their interests are to assist us in offering products to suit the needs of the users of this website.

## Newsletters

By subscribing to receive newsletters we will assume that you are providing us with your consent to send you marketing newsletters or notices either by mail, email, sms, social media and other electronic means provided to us by you. Whenever we send such marketing newsletters or notices, we will make it clear it is coming from 'Toys"R"US' (or 'ToysRUs', 'TRU' where abbreviation is required), and you will have the ability to unsubscribe or opt-out if you no longer wish to receive them. You may also contact us via our website contact form and request removal at any time.

## Disclosure of Personal Information to Third Parties

We may disclose your personal information to third parties for the purpose for which the information was collected or for related purposes, for example to complete a transaction on your behalf or provide you with a product that you purchased.  We engage third party contractors to perform services for us which involves the contractor handling personal information we hold. For example, we currently engage third party contractors to:

  * Deliver products purchased from this website.
  * Provide electronic funds transfer services, credit card account processing and related services.

In these situations, the third party contractor is strictly restricted from using any prohibited personal information about you except for the specific purpose for which we have supplied. We may also disclose your personal information to various law enforcement agencies and governments around the world for security, to comply with a subpoena, customs and immigration purposes.  Google may receive information about transactions conducted on this site for the purpose of product reviews or service reviews.  Other than the above, we will not disclose your personal information without your consent unless disclosure is either necessary to prevent a threat to life or health, authorised or required by law, reasonably necessary to enforce the law or necessary to investigate a suspected unlawful activity.

## Access & Correction of Information About You

We will, on request, provide you with access to the information we hold about you, unless there is an exception which applies under the National Privacy Principles, including for the purpose of correcting or updating that information.  We may recover from you our reasonable costs of supplying you with access to this information.  Your request to provide access to this information will be dealt with within in a reasonable time.  If we refuse to provide you with access to the information, we will provide you with reasons for the refusal and inform you of any exceptions relied upon under the National Privacy Principles.

## Keeping Your Personal Information Up To Date

We take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is accurate, complete, and up-to-date whenever we collect or use it.  If the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate, incomplete or out-of-date, please contact us and we will take reasonable steps to either correct this information, or if necessary, discuss alternative action with you.

## Updating/Accessing/Amending/Correcting Personally Identifiable Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may update it by making the change on our member account page or by emailing our Customer Support.

## Choice/Opt-Out

You may choose to stop receiving our newsletters (if you subscribe), marketing emails or marketing sms by clicking on a single link in the email or opting out in the case of sms, changing your account preferences under your account when logged in, or you can contact us.

## Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

We may use cookies or use web beacons or similar technologies, for example, to keep track of your preferences, profile information or in connection with the Google Customer Reviews Programme. Cookies are also used to collect general usage and volume statistical information that does not include personal information. They may further be used by third-party vendors to serve our ads to you across the internet based on your preferences or interests. You may choose to delete and block cookies whilst browsing this site.

## Links to Other Web Sites

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Toys"R"US.  If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies.  We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any web site you visit.

## Blogs, Reviews and Articles

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs, reviews or community forums.  You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them.

## Live Chat

We use a live chat feature to assist you with customer services.  If our chat feature is offline we will collect your name and email address so that we may reply to your request.  We will email you a full live chat history at end of live chat service.

## Surveys or Contests

From time-to-time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our site.  If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you.  Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information.  The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as post code).

## Security of Your Personal Information

We will securely hold your personal information and we will not trade, rent or sell it to third parties.

We will take all reasonable steps to keep secure any information which we hold about you. Personal information may be stored both electronically on our computer system, and in hard-copy form. Firewalls, SSL encryption, passwords, anti-virus software and email filters act to protect all our electronic information.

We take all necessary measures to ensure the security of hard-copy information.

Once your transaction is finalised, both the electronic and hard-copy information are securely archived.  After a period of 7 years, both the electronic and hard-copy information will be destroyed.

## Data Retention

If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Resolving Your Concerns

If you wish to gain access to your personal information, have a complaint about a breach of your privacy or you have any query on how your personal information is collected or used please forward your request, complaint or query to the address below.  We will respond to your query or complaint as soon as possible.

Post: The Privacy Officer, Box 4310, Dandenong South Vic 3164.

## Changes to This Privacy policy

We may amend this Privacy policy as our business requires or as the law changes. Any changes to this Privacy policy will be updated on www.toysrus.com.au, so please visit this page periodically to ensure that you have our most current privacy policy.
